Robert H. Taylor Collection of English and American Literature, 1280s-1958 (bulk 1800s-1930s ): Finding Aid
Princeton University Library. Department of Rare Books and Special Collections.
- Series 1: Modern (Bound) Manuscripts, 1600-1958; 7 shelves
  - WHITELOCKE, MARY, Memoir, circa 1660s; 226; AM 2016-50; 1 volume 175 pages, including blanks 12.6 x 7.5 cm Bound in contemporary embroidered binding
    An intimate and detailed autobiography of a wealthy Puritan gentry woman, Mary Whitelocke, the daughter of London merchant Bigley Carleton, in the mid-seventeenth century. Addressed to her eldest son, Whitelocke's memoir encompasses her life from the time of her first marriage at the age of 16 to Rowland Wilson (d. 1650), MP, also from a London mercantile family. Whitelocke's second marriage in 1650 was to the prominent lawyer and politician Bulstrode Whitelocke (1605-1675), with whom she had seven children. Written in a homiletic style with copious Biblical references in the margins, the memoir is characterised by distinctively feminine imagery: "...god deals with his people as a tender harted mother dus with her child at her breast, she puts some bitter thing upon the nipple not to hurt the child but to make the child care the less for the breast: so the lord dealt with me he put some bitter dispensation upon all my creature injoyments..." and primarily focuses on Whitelocke's family and domestic affairs, much of it given over to her children and their loving and pious behavior; she gives a poignant account of a miscarriage that occurred during her first marriage. Though, discussion of public affairs and events are also included, particularly Whitelocke's vigorous defence of her second husband's public life.
    "William Puzey" (ownership inscription). Previous acquisition: Bernard Quaritch.
    This manuscript is referred to and quoted in R.H. Whitelocke's Memoirs of Bulstrode Whitelocke (London, 1860), pp.283-88.
  - WILDE, OSCAR (1854-1900). "The Duchess of Padua.", 1880; 1 item 2 leaves
    Two non-consecutive leaves of autograph manuscript (fol. A and fol. B21), written on recto only.
  - WILDE, OSCAR (1854-1900). "An Ideal Husband.", circa 1890; 1 volume, 106 leaves
    Author's typewritten copy with autograph annotations.
  - WILDE, OSCAR (1854-1900). "Remarkable Series of Six Autograph Letters.", 1897-1899; 1 volume, 21 leaves
    Bound collection of autograph letters from Wilde to his publisher Leonard Smithers.
  - WILDE, OSCAR (1854-1900). "Scenario: the Cardinal of Avignon, a Tragedy in Four Acts.", circa 1882; 1 volume, 8 leaves
    Autograph manuscript of a portion of Act I, scene I of the unpublished play "The Cardinal of Avignon."
  - WILDE, OSCAR (1854-1900). "Unfinished Play.", circa 1879-1883; 1 volume, 61 leaves
    Autograph manuscript of an unfinished play with revisions, undated Signed with initials on fol. 38v, with approximately. 40 leaves in Wilde's hand. Appears to present the beginning of Act II as outlined in Wilde's scenario for his unpublished play "The Cardinal of Avignon."
  - WITHERS, GEORGE (1588-1667). "Wither's Poems.", circa 1810-1818; 173; 2 volume, 336; 465 pp.
    Early proofs of a two-volume edition of George Wither's poetical works (not issued until 1839-1847), edited by John Matthew Gutch, interleaved and heavily annotated by Lamb, J.M. Gutch, and Dr. John Nott. Also includes manuscript insertions including an ALS by Algernon Charles Swinburne, tipped in front of vol. 1; ALS to Mr. Spoor from Thomas J. Wise, dated 1910, laid in vol. 1; an engraving (proof) of Lamb by James Pulham with the inscription in pen "Jas Pulman Esq. from Charles Lamb."
  - YEATS, WILLIAM BUTLER (1865-1939). "The Land of Heart's Desire.", 1894; 1 volume 8 leaves
    Typescript of the child's part in the drama, with manuscript revisions by the author and others.
  - YEATS, WILLIAM BUTLER (1865-1939). "The Land of Heart's Desire.", 1894; 1 volume, 25 leaves
- Series 2: Artwork, 1600-1948; 17 oversize clamshell boxes
  Consists of a variety of items (many oversized, matted and/or framed) by William Blake, Max Beerbohm, Hablot Knight Browne, George Cruikshank, Edward Lear, John Everett Millais, William Makepeace Thackeray, Dante Gabriel Rossetti, J. M. W. Turner, members of the Brontë family, and others. Robert Taylor collected works by or relating to British authors, artists, and illustrators represented elsewhere in the Taylor Collection, both in manuscripts and printed books. Most of the artwork is individually matted and labeled in a series of 17 clamshell boxes, organized alphabetically by artist and size. An oil portrait of Alexander Pope, attributed to Jean-Baptiste Van Loo (1684-1745), is separately housed.
  Additional artwork can be found in RTC01's bound manuscripts series, including an album of sketches and drawings by William Makepeace Thackeray; Lionel Grimston Fawkes's 1874-1875 scrapbook of illustrations for Anthony Trollope's The Way We Live Now; India paper proofs of drawings for "Orley Farm" by John Everett Millais, circa 1860; an 1868 album of pen-and-ink drawings and photographs compiled by John Lockwood Kipling for a young Rudyard Kipling and his sister; and additional drawings by Max Beerbohm. Artwork can also be found in archival boxes containing literary manuscripts and correspondence, including letters with drawings by Edward Lear, William Makepeace Thackeray, and William Butler Yeats.
  Arranged alphabetically by artist, or title when artist is unknown.
  - Beardsley, Aubrey, 1872-1898, 1893; 1 box
    - Ink drawing, vignette for Le Morte d'Arthur, Vol. I, Book 1, 1893; 1 item (Box 23, Item 1)
    - Ink drawing, vignette for Le Morte d'Arthur, Vol. II, Book 9, 1893; 1 item (Box 23, Item 2)
  - Beerbohm, Max, 1872-1956, 1899-1946; 5 boxes
    - Caricature in pencil, "Author, Publisher and Printer", 1920; 1 item (Box 24, Item 1)
    - Caricature, "Mr. Arthur Balfour wishing he had been born in a simpler age," signed, 1907; 1 item (Box 24, Item 2)
    - Pencil drawing, self-portrait, "Me as I more or less am nowadays...," signed, 1946; 1 item (Box 24, Item 3)
    - Ink drawing on cardboard, self-portrait, with a red wax buttoniere, signed, undated; 1 item (Box 24, Item 4)
    - Caricature, "Mr. Brummell constricting his waist-belt incurs the envious displeasure of the King," signed, undated; 1 item (Box 24, Item 5)
    - Ink drawing for the cover of Caricatures of Twenty-five Gentlemen, showing man in top hat and clown ruff, unsigned, undated; 1 item (Box 24, Item 6)
    - Caricature, "Genus Beerbohmiense," signed, undated; 1 item (Box 33, Item 1)
    - Caricature in ink of Edmund Gosse, signed, undated; 1 item (Box 24, Item 7)
    - Caricature in pencil, "Miss F. K. recovering from boredom at Hampstead," with full-length self-portrait, 1907; 1 item (Box 25, Item 1)
    - Caricature, "Sir Henry Irving," signed, 1901; 1 item (Box 25, Item 2)
    - Caricature in pencil, "A Milestone," signed, 1913; 1 item (Box 33, Item 2)
    - Caricature, "Mr. Joseph Pennell thinking of the Old 'Un," signed, 1913; 1 item 9.25" x 11" (Box 25, Item 3)
    - Caricature in pencil and ink, "Revisiting the Glimpses," signed, 1911; 1 item (Box 33, Item 3)
    - Caricature of Charles Algernon Swinburne, inscribed "Sophia for Philip" and signed, 1928; 1 item 8.25" x 14.5" (Box 25, Item 4)
    - Caricature, "Mr. Tennyson reading In Memoriam to his Sovereign," inscribed "For Nicholson, William and Mabel from Max", 1904; 1 item (Box 25, Item 5)
    - Caricature, "The Theatre of the Future: The Acting Manager," signed, 1922; 1 item (Box 25, Item 6)
    - Caricature, "The Theatre of the Future: The Call Boy," signed, 1922; 1 item (Box 25, Item 7)
    - Caricature, "The Theatre of the Future: The Managing Director...," signed, 1922; 1 item (Box 26, Item 1)
    - Caricature, "The Theatre of the Future: Orlando...Ex Seminarist Smith, Rosalind...Ex Seminarist Robinson," signed, 1922; 1 item (Box 26, Item 2)
    - Caricature (inscription only), "The Theatre of the Future: The Public," signed, 1922; 1 item (Box 26, Item 3)
    - Caricature of Reggie Turner in full-length profile, facing left, hands in pockets, with 3 other heads of Turner on same sheet, undated; 1 item (Box 26, Item 4)
    - Pencil-and-wash drawing, "President Wilson Visiting Congress," signed by the artist, 1919; 1 item (Box 33, Item 4)
    - Caricature in ink of W. B. Yeats and Edward Martyn, "Celtades Ambo," signed, 1899; 1 item (Box 26, Item 5)
    - Caricature, "Sir Charles Wyndham Defying Time", 1907; 1 item (Box 35, Item 1)
    - Folder of photographs of various illustrations and caricatures (including a stone bust by Oscar Nemon) of Max Beerbohm; 1931 January Beerbohm calendar by Ladbroke & Co., Ltd. (matted), 1931 January; Caricatures (prints) of: Sir Oswald Mosley, Rev. P. B. Clayton, John Masefield, J. L. Garvin, Siegfried Sassoon, Dean Inge(?), Lord Craik, H, G. Wells, "One Fine Morning" (large group of men with caption "Now they might undo me." Signed Max.), 1911-1931; 1 box (Box 37)
  - Bentley, Nicolas, 1907-1978, undated; portion of 1 box
    - Pen-and-ink caricature of Samuel Pepys, undated 6" x 7", mounted on same board with a second pen-and-ink caricature of Richard Brinsley Sheridan, 7.5" x 5.5", 1 item (Box 27, Item 1)
  - Blake, William, 1757-1827, 1780-1789; portions of 2 boxes
    - Pencil drawing, "The Archer," 6 1/2" x 8", undated; 1 item (Box 27, Item 2)
    - Pen-and-watercolor drawing, "The Landing of Brutus in England", 1780s; 1 item (Box 27, Item 3)
    - Pen-and-watercolor drawing, "The Landing of Julius Caesar in Britain", 1780s; 1 item (Box 27, Item 4)
    - Pencil drawing, kneeling figure of a nude demon, 6 1/2" x 7 3/8", undated; 1 item (Box 27, Item 5)
    - Pencil drawing, "Non Angli sed Angeli," 12 3/4" x 18 1/2", undated; 1 item (Box 34, Item 1)
  - Brontë, Anne, 1820-1849, 1836 May 30; portion of 1 box
    - Untitled drawing of an English landscape with a building, man, and dog, signed "Anne Brontë", 1836 May 30; 1 item (Box 27, Item 6)
  - Brontë, Charlotte, 1816-1855, 1830-1833; portion of 1 box
    - Oil painting, "Flowers," painted by Charlotte Brontë when she was about 14 years old and presented to Mary Wright Haworth; presented as a memorial by Haworth to Miss Eliza Watson on 1861 October 30, circa 1830; 1 item (Box 27, Item 7)
    - Pencil drawing, "Santa Maria, September 23 [18]33," signed, 6" x 4.25"; note on back - "This drawing was executed by Charlotte Brontë & given by me - her husband - to Miss E. Taylor. A. B. Nicholls", 1 item (Box 27, Item 8)
  - Brontë, Emily, 1818-1848, 1832 December 8; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil drawing of a ruined castle and a cottage beside a ravine, signed "E. J. Brontë," presumably copied from an engraving, 1832 December 8; 1 item (Box 27, Item 9)
  - Browne, Hablot K. (artist known as "Phiz"), 1815-1882, undated; 1 box
    - Pencil drawing, illustration for Trollope's Can You Forgive Her?, "Dear Greenow, Dear Husband," 5" x 7", undated; 1 item (Box 28, Item 1)
    - Watercolor, "The most self willed young woman I ever saw in my life!," illustration for Trollope's Can You Forgive Her?, undated; 1 item (Box 28, Item 2)
    - Pencil drawing, illustration for Trollope's Can You Forgive Her?, "Then, Then, Then let her come to me," 5" x 7", undated; 1 item (Box 28, Item 3)
    - Watercolor, title page for "The Diadem", undated; 1 item (Box 28, Item 4)
    - Watercolor, "Florence and Edith on the staircase," illustration for Dickens' Dombey and Son, undated; 1 item (Box 28, Item 5)
    - Pencil drawing, "Nicholas congratulates Arthur Gride on his Wedding Morning," undated illustration at page 543 of Dickens' Nicholas Nickleby, with Dickens' suggestions for alterations in the drawing written in ink beneath, 1 item (Box 28, Item 6)
    - Wash drawing, "Mrs. Leo Hunter's Fancy Dress Dejeuner," from Dickens' Pickwick Papers, with 4-line comment in Dickens' hand, undated; 1 item (Box 28, Item 7)
  - Bunbury, Henry William, 1750-1811, 1770; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil sketch, Oliver Goldsmith, used as frontispiece for Goldsmith's Haunch of Venison (1776), circa 1770; 1 item (Box 29, Item 1)
  - Burton, Frederic William, 1816-1900, 1865; portion of 1 box
    - Charcoal study for portrait of George Eliot, in the National Gallery in London, 1865; 1 item (Box 34, Item 2)
  - Byron, George Gordon. Miniature Portrait of Byron by unidentified artist, undated; portion of 1 box (Box 29, Item 2)
  - Cruikshank, George, 1792-1878, 1831; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil and watercolor drawing for "Thoughts About People," from Sketches By Boz, watermarked, 1831; 1 item (Box 30, Item 1)
    - Pencil sketch, "The Bloomsbury Christening," from Sketches By Boz, 4.5" x 6.75", undated; 1 item (Box 30, Item 2)
  - Dadd, Richard, 1819-1887, 1840; portion of 1 box
    - Pen-and-ink drawing, illustration for Boccaccio's Decameron, 5.5" x 7.5", circa 1840; 1 item (Box 30, Item 3)
  - De Morgan, William, 1839-1917, dates not examined; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil study of a woman's head, 5.75" x 4.5", undated; 1 item (Box 30, Item 4)
  - Doyle, Richard, 1824-1883, 1848; portion of 1 box
    - Frontispiece for Leigh Hunt's A Jar of Honey from Mount Hybla, 1848; 1 item (Box 30, Item 5)
    - Pencil drawing of Lord Tennyson (individual), undated; 1 item (Box 30, Item 6)
    - Pencil drawing of Lord Tennyson (group), undated; 1 item (Box 30, Item 7)
  - Eves, Reginald, 1876-1941, 1923; portion of 1 box
    - Thomas Hardy portrait in fixed charcoal, 1923; 1 item (Box 34, Item 3)
  - Hill, Gertrude, 1940; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil sketch of Robert H. Taylor, 1940; 1 folder (Box 30, Folder 8)
  - Isabey, Jean-Baptiste, 1767-1855, undated; portion of 1 box
    - Graphite and sepia wash drawing, portrait of Lord Byron, 10.25" x 8", undated; 1 item (Box 30, Item 9)
  - Lancaster, Osbert, 1908-1986, 1948; portion of 1 box
    - "Sir Max Beerbohm Fenestrating", 1948; 1 item (Box 30, Item 10)
  - Laurence, Samuel, 1812-1888, 1864; 1 box
    - Portrait of William Makepeace Thackeray, chalk and charcoal, 1864; 1 item (Box 39, Item 1)
    - Portrait of Anthony Trollope, chalk and charcoal, 1864; 1 item (Box 39, Item 2)
  - Lear, Edward, 1812-1888, 1826-1867; portion of 1 box
    - Watercolor, "Mt. Athos by Moonlight", undated; 1 item (Box 31, Item 1)
    - Ink and wash, distant view of Mt. Etna, circa 1843; 1 item (Box 31, Item 2)
    - Watercolor of a Nile scene, 1867; 1 item (Box 31, Item 3)
    - Pencil drawing, "Pavia," with numbers listed indicating colors to be used, 11" x 4.5", 1841; 1 item (Box 31, Item 4)
    - Pencil drawing of Salmona, 1845; 1 item (Box 31, Item 5)
    - Watercolor, "Yellow Iris", 1826; 1 item (Box 31, Item 6)
  - Leech, John, 1817-1864, undated; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil drawing, illustration for Trollope's Can You Forgive Her?, "‘I have heard,’ said Burgo," (Vol. I, Chapter XXVIII), undated; 1 item (Box 31, Item 7)
  - Lewis, E. Goodwyn, 1827-1891, 1869; portion of 1 box
    - Portrait of Charles Dickens, pastel, 1869; 1 item (Box 36, Item 1)
  - Martin, John, 1789-1854, 1836-1847; portions of 2 boxes
    - Watercolor painting, coastal landscape scene, signed, 11.5" x 21.5", 1847; 1 item (Box 34, Item 4)
    - Pen-and-ink and wash drawing, romantic landscape, signed, 9.25" x 5.75", 1836; 1 item (Box 31, Item 8)
  - Millais, John Everett, 1829-1896, 1829-1864; portion of 1 box
    - Pen drawing by Millais at age 14, signed and dated 1843, titled "Edmund last King of the East Angles martyred by Honguor The Dane," matted, 1 item (Box 31, Item 9)
    - Pencil and watercoloring drawing, "Was it not a lie?," 1860, made for a wood-engraved illustration for Anthony Trollope's Framley Parsonage (1861) 27.4 x 21.5 cm., 1 item (Box 31, Item 10)
    - Watercolor and gouache painting, "Stript off the case and read the naked shield, Elaine" illustration for Tennyson's Idylls of the King, 1862; 1 item (Box 31, Item 11)
    - Illustration for Anthony Trollope's Small House at Allingham, 1864; 1 item (Box 31, Item 12)
    - Color print of the Trollope Family by Childs and Inman, Lithographers (based on 1829 sketch), 1 item (Box 31, Item 13)
  - Nerli, Girolamo Pieri, 1860-1926, 1892; 1 box
    - Portrait of Robert Louis Stevenson, framed, 1892; 1 item (Box 38, Item 1)
  - Nicholson, William, Sir, 1872-1949, 1929 April 21; portion of 1 box
    - Tinted ink sketch, "A Fact (little known): Narrow escape of the Lord Chancelor on 1929 April 21 at 4:45", 1 item (Box 31, Item 14)
  - Persian miniature with accompanying text. Persia, 17th century (?). The image depicts the angels worshipping Adam. The text is a poetical account of the creation of Adam as God's deputy (khalīfah) on earth and is based on Qur'ān 2:30ff., circa 17th century; portion of 1 box (Box 31, Item 15)
  - Richardson, Jonathan, 1665-1745, undated; portion of 1 box
    - Crayon painting (pastel) of Alexander Pope, after the Godfrey Kneller portrait from Strawberry Hill, attributed to Richardson, with an autograph receipt by Pope to Bernard Whalley for his subscription to Pope's Iliad, undated; 1 item (Box 32, Item 1)
  - Rooker, Michael Angelo, 1746-1801, 1775; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil and watercolor drawing for Laurence Sterne's The Life and Opinions of Tristram Shandy, showing Trim, holding a pair of boots, interrupting Uncle Toby and Tristram Shandy's father, 5.25" x 3.13", signed by Rooker, 1775; 1 item (Box 32, Item 2)
  - Rossetti, Dante Gabriel, 1828-1882, 1857; portion of 1 box
    - Ink drawing, "Fanny Cornforth," 5" x 3.88", undated; 1 item (Box 32, Item 3)
    - Pen-and-ink study for the "Vision of the Sane Grael," 10" x 8.88", 1857; 1 item (Box 32, Item 4)
  - Rothenstein, William, 1872-1945, undated; portion of 1 box
    - Charcoal and chalk drawing of Aubrey Beardsley, signed, undated; 1 item (Box 34, Item 5)
  - Rowlandson, Thomas, 1756-1827, 1802; portion of 1 box
    - Pen over pencil drawing, View of Horace Walpole's Strawberry Hill, 8.25" x 5.13", undated; 1 item (Box 32, Item 5)
    - Pen and watercolor drawing, "Lord Cardigan making preparations to attend his majesty's levee," signed by Rowlandson, 1802; 1 item (Box 32, Item 6)
  - Ruskin, John, 1819-1900, 1846; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil and watercolor drawing of Chamonix, 1846; 1 item (Box 32, Item 7)
  - Ryley, Charles Reuben, 1752?-1798, 1788; portion of 1 box
    - Pen-and-ink drawing with gray wash of Mr. Ryder in the Character of Lovegold, circa 1788. Illustration for Henry Fielding, The Miser: A Comedy (IV:5 "The Miser Scene"). Signed and inscribed, "Give me my money again, villain", 1 item (Box 32, Item 8)
  - Strang, William, 1859-1921, 1907-1910; portion of 1 box
    - Portrait of Thomas Hardy, 1910. Drypoint (final state), printed by David Strang, 1 item (Box 32, Item 9)
    - Portrait of George Bernard Shaw, 1907. Drypoint (final state), printed by David Strang, 1 item (Box 32, Item 10)
  - Thackeray, William Makepeace, 1811-1863, 1857; portion of 1 box
    - Pencil and crayon sketch, self-portrait, signed, 1857; 1 item (Box 32, Item 11)
  - Turner, J. M. W. (Joseph Mallord William), 1775-1851, 1791; portion of 1 box
    - First sketch of group of fish for Turner's "Slaver," purchased by John Ruskin (with note saying he purchased it from Ruskin's housekeeper, Mrs. Booth) in 1880, undated; 1 item (Box 32, Item 12)
    - Pen-and-watercolor, "View of Rochester Castle & Bridge," signed by Turner, 1791; 1 item (Box 32, Item 13)
  - Westall, Richard, 1765-1836, undated; portion of 1 box
    - Watercolor drawing, illustration of an episode from Ossian, "Fingal meets Coban-carglas, daughter of King Torcul-torno," undated 22.86" x 19.75", 1 folder (Box 36, Folder 2)
      Exhibited in "Visions of Antiquity: Neoclassic Figure Drawing" at the Los Angeles County Museum of Art (1993 July 22-1993 September 19), the Philadelphia Museum of Art (1993 October 30-1994 January 2), and the Minneapolis Institute of Arts (1994 February 6-1994 April 3).
- Series 3: Modern Manuscripts (Unbound) and Correspondence, 1545-1969; 23 archival boxes
  Consists of files for individual authors that contain correspondence, documents, and unbound manuscripts (including some smaller sized items of art) that were previously housed in file cabinet drawers in the Taylor Room Library. The folders in each box are filed alphabetically by author name.
  Arranged alphabetically by author or collector.
  - A Wood, Anthony, 1632-1695, dates not examined; 1 folder
    (see: Wood, Anthony)
  - A.E. (Russell, George William), 1867-1935, undated; 1 folder
    - 2 manuscripts of verse (1904) with notes to [the Duchess of Sutherland]: "The Wind of Angus" (1 p.) and "Aphrodite" (1 p.), dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Addison, Joseph, 1672-1719, 1704-1717; 2 folders
    - 2 letters: 1 to [Edward Wortley Montagu], 1711; 1 to William Conolly, 1714 1 document, 1704, 1 folder (Folder 2)
    - 1 letter to Ambrose Phillips, 1710 1 letter to "Mr. Worsley," 1717, 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Alcott, Louisa May, 1832-1888, 1875-1880; 2 folders
    - 1 letter to her nephews, 1875; 1 folder (Folder 4)
    - Jack and Jill 1880, 6 manuscript leaves, 1 folder (Folder 5)
  - Allston, Washington, 1779-1843, undated; 1 folder
    - "Sonnet on the late Samuel Taylor Coleridge," 1 p., undated; 1 folder (Folder 6)
  - Anstey, Christopher, 1724-1805, 1788; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to Mr. Dodsley, 1788; 1 folder (Folder 7)
  - Arnold, Matthew, 1822-1888, 1866-1884; 1 folder
    - 17 letters 1866-1884: 1 to Mrs. Davenport Adams, 1 to Rev. H. Allen, 1 to Walter Richard Cassels, 2 to "My dear Craik," 1 to "Mr. Macgregor," 2 to Alexander Macmillan, 1 to H.C. Merivale, 1 to Charles Myhill, 1 to Mrs. Palmer, 1 to "Mr. Scherer," 1 to "My dear Smally," 1 to Mrs. Smally, 2 to Lucy Toulmin Smith, 1 to unidentified person, 1 folder (Folder 8)
  - Austen, Cassandra Elizabeth, 1773-1845, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - 6 letters ([1837]-1844) to "Anna" (Mrs. B. Lefroy), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Austen, Cassandra Leigh, 1739-1827, undated; portion of 1 folder
    - 8 letters (1810-1820) to "Anna" (Mrs. B. Lefroy), dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 9)
  - Austen, Francis William, Sir, 1774-1865, 1817; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to B. Lefroy, telling of sister Jane's death, 1817; 1 folder (Folder 10)
  - Austen, Jane, 1775-1817, 1811 November 9; 1 folder
    - 2 letters (1805-1808) to sister, Cassandra (RHT) 19th -750.1 OVERSIZE, dates not examined; portion of 1 folder (Folder 11)
    - The Morning Chronicle, 1811 November 9 (1st advertisement of Sense and Sensibility), portion of 1 folder (Folder 11)
  - Ayloffe, John, d. 1685, 1670-1679; 1 folder
    - manuscript copy of "Marvel's Ghost," attributed to Ayloffe, 2 pp, 1670s; 1 folder (Folder 12)
  - Bacon, Francis, Sir, 1561-1626, 1601 April 22-1614; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to "Auditor Sutton," 1614 manuscript of "Elegancies Miscellany" said to be in the hand of Bacon, 1 leaf, dated 1601 April 22, 1 folder (Folder 1)
  - Barrett, Lawrence, 1838-1891, undated; 1 folder
    - 3 letters (undated-1890) to Oscar Wilde, dates not examined; 1 folder (Folder 2)
  - Barton, Bernard, 1784-1849, 1820-1845; 1 folder
    - 2 manuscripts of verse (in the form of letters to John Mitford); 8 letters 1820-1845: 1 to William Stevenson Hitch, 1 to Thomas Hervey, 2 to John Mitford, 1 to George Virtue, 3 to unidentified people, 1 folder (Folder 3)
  - Baxter, Richard, 1615-1691, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 letter to unidentified person, undated; 1 folder (Folder 4)
  - Beardsley, Aubrey Vincent, 1872-1898, undated; 1 folder
    - 1 manuscript of "Punch and Judy", undated; 10 pp. (Folder 5)
  - Beerbohm, Max, Sir, 1872-1956, 1887-1956; 3 boxes
    - Caricatures I, 1890-1899; 1 folder
      - 24 sheets of drawings and caricatures from his undergraduate days at Oxford, 1890s; 1 folder (Box 4, Folder 1)
    - Caricatures II, 1889-1946; 1 folder